Contact

nitin_pri@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/nitinvengurlekar-55349447 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

ΑI

Supervised Learning Generative Al

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)

Marathi (Professional Working)

Certifications

Oracle Cloud Infrastructure 2023 Al Certified Foundations Associate

Certified Architect Microsoft Azure Solutions

Oracle Cloud Infrastructure 2018 Architect Associate

Oracle Autonomous Database Cloud 2019 Certified Specialist

ZFS Specialist

Honors-Awards

VMware vExpert

Collin College Curriculum Advisory Board - Computer Systems/Web & Mobile Applications Advisory Committee

Publications

Oracle ASM 12c Pocket Reference Guide: Database Cloud Storage

Oracle 11g Automatic Storage Management

Oracle Data Guard 11g Handbook Oracle ASM 12c Pocket Reference Guide

Oracle Exadata Expert's HandBook

Nitin Vengurlekar

Chief Technology Strategist & Distinguished Mission Systems Architect Federal Government, Defense & Intelligence Coppell, Texas, United States

Summary

Nitin Vengurlekar is the Chief Technology Strategist in Oracle Government and Education organization, with two primary areas of focus

Inbound role - Sales Enablement and Solution Strategy messaging for GovEd organization, with primary focus on Data Management

Outbound role - Build strategic relationships with SLED, Federal Cexecs, Thought Leadership and build awareness of Oracle solutions at Oracle & Industry Conferences

Prior to joining Oracle, Nitin Vengurlekar was the co-founder and CTO of Viscosity North America, where his team was Gold Partner for AWS and Oracle OCI, implementing countless Cloud and onpremise solutions, including ExaCS, ExaCC/C@C, and Exadata systems, as well as Full stack Data Platforms

Nitin has authored some of the most foundational books in the industry:

Oracle Automatic Storage Management Exadata Handbook

Data Guard Deployment Guide and Real World Experiences . Nitin sits on the curriculum board for the following colleges:

Collin College - Computer Systems/Web & Mobile Applications Advisory Committee

Dallas Colleges (DCCCD) - Cloud Curriculum Advisory Board

Nitin is an Oracle ACE Director and also an VMware vExpert. Both of these titles are considered to be highest recognition in their respective areas.

In a previous Oracle stint- Nitin worked for Oracle for more than 17 years. Key areas across the 17 years included:

Database Cloud Architect/Evangelist in Oracle's Cloud Strategy Group in charge of Private Database Cloud messaging.

Key member of the Real Application Cluster (RAC) engineering group and RAC Product Management Team. Main emphasis was on ASM, Virtualization (VMware & OVM), 3rd Party Storage Integration, & RAC integration.

Key contributor in helping build & instantiate the Oracle-EMC Joint Escalation Center (JSC). Included support enablement and content generation for the center.

Nitin is a well-known Oracle technologist and speaker in the areas of Oracle Storage, high availability, Oracle RAC, and private database cloud. He has written many papers on storage, database tuning, and served as a contributor to Oracle documentation as well as Oracle education material.

Experience

Oracle

5 years 7 months

Chief Technology Strategist/Distinguished Architect Federal Government, Defense & Intelligence November 2019 - Present (5 years 7 months)

Dallas/Fort Worth Area

Chief Technology Strategist November 2019 - Present (5 years 7 months)

Viscosity North America CTO/Architect/Service Delivery/Cloud Evangelist August 2012 - November 2019 (7 years 4 months) Dallas/Fort Worth Area

Responsible for Business development and Partner relationship management. Work with Oracle, Cisco, IBM/Lenovo, VMware to create partnered solutions

My focus is and always been, providing customers with thought leadership and guidance on [right] technology and architecture for highly available systems.

Implementation of numerous Virtualization and High Availability solutions; including deployment of key HA solutions for SOA DR, Hybrid cloud build-outs, and large scale RAC.

Key accomplishments:

- Implemented Oracle DBaaS on Oracle RAC for one of largest Wall Street
 Trading customers
- Large scale consolidation with Oracle RAC On the Exadata Engineered System Platform
- Migrated one of world largest Siebel CRM implementation from AIX/DB2 to UCS Linux and

Oracle using GoldenGate

• Implemented Zero-downtime migration from iSeries to Linux for large Real Estate / Financial

customer

• Implemented Oracle SOA for High Availability with Oracle Service Bus, Web Services, and

Orchestration of ERP, CRM, and Web Services into Business Operation and Processes

A little bit about Viscosity:

Viscosity North America specializes in helping customers maximize their investment in Oracle and SQL Server technologies. We specialize in Oracle on virtualization platforms, Oracle RAC, performance tuning, and full-stack architecture support. We have a world-class organization that excels in Database Migration, Virtualizing Oracle, Exadata Consolidation Deployment, Tuning and Exadata Patching.

Oracle

Technical Director

January 1995 - August 2012 (17 years 8 months)

Technical Director - Product Strategy/Cloud Evangelist

Responsibilities included:

Developed Private Database Cloud Architecture Guide and worked across Oracle engineering

organizations to support the Cloud architecture.

Developed Private Database Cloud Customer Messaging program. Presented this messaging to Top

Tier Oracle customers across 18 countries

Built Private Database Cloud Curriculum for Oracle University

RAC and ASM Development

Responsibilities included:

Technical Product Manager for Oracle Automatic Storage Management (ASM).

Develop and evangelize Oracle storage best practices, work with Storage

Alliance partners (EMC, Symantec, Hitachi, HP) for certification

Worked towards successful Oracle RAC/ASM migration with large customers

Assist RACPACK customers from project start to production and finally to customer referencability

Sabre Holdings

Technical Architect - Unix/Oracle/DB2 Systems January 1990 - January 1995 (5 years 1 month)

Ft. Worh, Texas

Responsible for automation of system and database deployment Worked as Storage, System and DBA Lead role for Airline Solution system deployments.

Built Tier1, Tier2 and Tier3 support structures for production support
Responsible reviewing and incorporating new Oracle and Informix database
features as well as complimentary OS (Sun Solaris, AIX, HP) few features
Helped implement a mentoring program for junior DBAs
Primary liaison for Oracle Sales and Support

Sprint Nextel

MVS/DB2 Systems Programmer June 1987 - January 1990 (2 years 8 months)

Installing MVS software, CBPDO, CBMSO, and front-end interface to all IPL systems. In additiona, vendor relatioship management for all OEM based products

Education

Western Illinois University
Bachelor's of Science, Chemistry · (1985 - 1987)

Ohio Northern University
Pharmacy, Chemistry · (1982 - 1985)

Wheeling High School (1979 - 1982)